BON APPÉTIT, YOUR MAJESTY
Who goes there?
Is this a revolt?
What about His Majesty?
What happened to him?
YI HEON
KING OF JOSEON
Your Majesty,
you must get out of here immediately!
Your Majesty!
Who are you?
Can you not tell? We are jesters!
Drop your sword!
Cook Yeon, we must go right now.
Cook Yeon.
You, above all, must be safe.
The purge hasn't even happened.
What's happening?
Tell me, Gong-gil.
I saw the guards wearing red headbands.
Is this…
It is treason.
Treason?
Who's leading it?
Grand Prince Jesan and his followers.
They already killed Im Seo-hong,
the Second Minister of Works.
They were targeting you next.
That is why I hurriedly got you out.
Me?
What about His Majesty? Where is he?
I do not know yet.
The best you can do now is hide.
What are you saying?
I must see His Majesty right now.
Did you not hear me say
they are after you?
Are you that worried about him?
Yes.
I guess you're not.
What if you go back and they capture you?
Do you not see it?
You must stay alive.
That is the way to help His Majesty.
His Majesty tried so hard
to restrain himself.
How could this happen?
It is rather odd that Her Royal Highness
summoned us at this hour.
Do you think
she heard about our gathering?
I believe she has finally
made up her mind.
She did witness
His Majesty's madness unleash after all.
We will see soon enough.
Let us hurry.
-Yes, my lord.
Your Highness, what are you doing here?
And for what reason
are you holding a sword?
I am here to uphold a royal command.
A royal command?
The command
to eliminate the treacherous
Han family, who, reveled in power,
manipulated the nation from the shadows.
Then it was not
Her Royal Highness who summoned us?
How dare you!
Do you not fear the heavens?
The heavens?
The heavens, you say?
Do not worry.
For your death will go down as the doing
of the current king, the tyrant.
What?
Do not shut the gate!
May you rest in peace.
-No!
-Do not shut the gate! Let us out!
Mother, I am so afraid.
It is all right.
It will be all right.
GRAND PRINCE JINMYEONG
YI HEON'S HALF BROTHER
QUEEN DOWAGER JAHYEON
YI HEON'S STEPMOTHER
Grand Prince Jesan.
Your Royal Highness.
A disaster has befallen us.
That is why I came to you in haste.
What is this disaster you speak of?
Brace yourself for the news.
His Majesty lost his mind
and murdered the Grand Royal Queen Dowager
and slaughtered
all the court officials indiscriminately.
Then
are you saying Her Royal Highness…
has passed away?
I reached her too late.
And so I hurriedly gathered
the officials of the Sarim faction
and entered the palace,
risking discourtesy,
to protect Your Royal Highness
and Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
Then where is His Majesty right now?
He went to Salgoji Forest
to battle the rebel forces
who rose to hold him responsible
for his madness.
Battle, you say?
Mother.
Are you all right?
Jinmyeong.
What should we do now?
Your Royal Highness.
It is time
for Grand Prince Jinmyeong
to ascend the throne.
What did you just say?
How could you say such a thing
when His Majesty is still alive?
Are you saying you want my Jinmyeong
to become a rebel leader?
Do you truly…
not see
who the tyrant's blade…
will come for next?
Before His Majesty becomes a threat
to you and Grand Prince Jinmyeong,
he must be dethroned.
Even so…
Jinmyeong is still too young.
Must we…
shed even more blood
for you to listen to me?
Three days.
Give me three days
to contemplate the matter.
Her Royal Highness' funeral--
I cannot.
The throne must not be left vacant
for even one day.
The coronation will be held
as soon as dawn breaks tomorrow.
That is final.
What if His Majesty were to return?
How will you handle the consequences?
This time…
it will be almost impossible
for him to return alive.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty…
Your Majesty!
COURSE N° 12 HWANSEBAN
Your Royal Highness.
A calamity has struck the palace,
so we brought the royal seal to you.
Bring it forth.
This was sent from Sangseowon,
Office of the Royal Seal.
We request your wise counsel,
Your Royal Highness.
Inform the Ministry of Rites
that Her Royal Highness
will do what is right to honor
the royal ancestors and the state,
uphold order within the court,
and calm the disarray.
The coronation for the new king
will be held soon,
so instruct all officials
to prepare to show their respect.
Yes, Your Highness.
Please issue the royal edict.
ROYAL EDICT: OFFICIAL DOCUMENT
CONTAINING THE KING'S COMMAND
Very well.
I will write the edict.
However, it will not simply include
the matter of the coronation,
but also a pledge for a new era.
I understand.
I, too, will take part in presenting
a new world to our people
alongside Grand Prince Jinmyeong,
who will soon ascend the throne.
Have you heard?
The king lost his mind last night,
murdered his own grandmother,
and indiscriminately slaughtered
the court officials.
And after committing such a heinous act,
-he left to hunt!
-How ridiculous!
The current king will be dethroned,
and a new king will ascend the throne.
Who will be the new king?
Grand Prince Jinmyeong.
He will soon ascend the throne.
Word is that the king died
in a hunting accident.
-The king has passed? Is that true?
-Yes.
I heard he was burned to death.
-He was punished by the heavens.
-Indeed.
CORONATION
Our nation has been cultivating virtue
for one hundred years,
and by doing so,
it has let down strong and healthy roots.
Unfortunately,
our current king neglected his duties,
crushing the people's trust
and plunging them into distress.
-For the sake of our nation…
-…and its people,
by the mandate of the heavens,
Grand Prince Jinmyeong
will be appointed as the new king
and shall ascend the throne
as the 11th King of Joseon.
As the new king,
may he rule wisely
and save his people from their concerns.
Long live the king.
-Long live the king!
The reign of the tyrant is over at last.
Congratulations.
Your efforts for this very day
have finally paid off.
I owe this glory to you all
who have assisted me throughout.
Soon, the people will offer you
their support and favor.
You should ascend the throne then.
And become a sage king for us all.
-Become a sage king for us.
My goodness.
It has been less than half a day
since our new king ascended the throne.
Save your breath.
-Yes, Your Highness.
What happened to His Majesty
after he went to Salgoji Forest?
They say there were no survivors,
so it seems
no one has made it through last night.
I find it odd
that the chief royal cook
found out and got away.
Do not worry.
With His Majesty gone from the palace,
the chief royal cook's life
is at its close.
That's impossible.
His Majesty had agreed to eat
with the Grand Royal Queen Dowager.
So why would he harm her?
Or his subjects?
A new king ascended the throne overnight.
There is nothing we can do now.
If Grand Prince Jinmyeong
ascended the throne,
what's going to happen to His Majesty?
Upon hearing you were taken
by a band of rebels,
he went to Salgoji Forest,
and he has not been seen since.
He went all the way there because of me?
They say there were piles of dead bodies
at Salgoji Forest.
No one has found his body yet,
but it is unlikely he survived.
It can't be.
I shall go out and see
if I can get more news.
Wait here until I get back.
Wait.
Take this.
Please find His Majesty
and give this to him.
Tell him I'm safe.
I shall.
Court Lady Kim…
I cannot believe you died
such a futile death.
I do not understand what is happening.
How can everything change overnight?
I hope our chief royal cook
is somewhere safe.
It worries me that she just vanished.
It worries me too.
She left without a word to me.
If she returned to the future
that she said she came from,
I would not be so worried.
What are you talking about?
Our chief royal cook came from the future?
-Well…
-Are you all right, Maid Seo?
Are you not feeling well?
-No, it is--
-There is already enough madness
in the palace as it is.
-Get a hold of yourself.
-This is so frustrating!
Why can you not believe me?
This is why
she did not tell any of you about it.
Miss…
Is it true that His Majesty lost his mind
and plunged the palace into chaos?
He did have fits,
but nothing like this has ever happened.
I find it hard to believe.
How have you all been?
Your Majesty.
Where are you?
Who are you?
Are you Korean?
Could she be a gwinyeo?
No, stop it.
Halt!
I command that she be immediately
appointed as the chief royal cook!
Now that I've survived
the harrowing, difficult times…
A true cook
does not blame the lack of time,
but selects good ingredients
to create an exquisite dish.
…I realize
that you always made me
want to become a better chef.
I do not wish to eat anything tonight.
Now, if you're not there to eat my food,
I have no reason to cook.
Promise me…
that you will never
let yourself get hurt again.
I can finally be honest with my feelings.
I miss you…
Your Majesty.
It is an ambush!
Are you saying
you lost the dethroned king?
If what he says is true,
is this not a disaster, Your Highness?
I apologize, Your Highness.
I will bring you his head
within three days.
Leave it.
A tiger that has lost its territory
can do nothing but roar out in rage.
Lord Yoo.
You may enter.
The remnants of Urimwi
ambushed the North Gate.
What?
Urimwi launched an ambush?
What should we do?
We have a new king,
so this stands as an act of treason.
What more can a dethroned king
who is on the run do?
Your Highness!
We urgently request your presence.
Why must it be so hard
to enter my own home?
Consort Kang,
I truly hoped you were not one of them.
I thought you harmed Jinmyeong
only out of jealousy toward my cook.
I see the hands that used to console me…
were hiding a blade.
I waited for this day to come
from the very beginning.
I will not seek
your understanding or forgiveness.
Yes. That is what I expect of you.
But do not forget this.
One who bears a sword with a grin…
will eventually be struck by it.
Uncle.
You are back, Your Majesty.
Yes.
I am back alive.
We must have one final conversation.
I see the preparations at Salgoji Forest
were not sufficient.
They were more than sufficient.
However,
you chose the wrong ground for the battle.
You wanted the people to think
the tyrannical king who killed his own kin
went hunting in Salgoji Forest,
where he was punished by the heavens.
Is that not right?
However,
you overlooked the fact that
I am familiar with the terrain there.
Now I see why my men lost you.
So, did you leave for the forest
fully aware of the disaster
that would befall the palace?
Were you also aware I was behind the plot?
I realized
right before I left for the forest.
I just was not certain.
Do explain how.
"The edges of objects
are always harder to see,
and when you sleep,
be sure to lock the latch securely."
That was the message.
It is a riddle based on
the sounds of characters.
Did Tang Bailong
try to send me a message with a riddle?
Je for "edge."
San for "latch."
JESAN
I see the Ming cook
has spoken out of turn.
Either way, you lost.
Do you not agree?
It must be retribution
for the Muin Literati Purge.
Then are you prepared to accept
whatever punishment is given to you?
I have already been dethroned.
What more do you want from me?
You resented your grandmother
and her Han family so much,
and it was I
who killed them on your behalf,
was it not?
Now,
it is time for you
to take full responsibility.
It is true
that I once wanted them all dead.
However, I was going to reconcile
with my grandmother.
What if you did?
What would that have changed?
What about the lives
of the loyal subjects you killed
during the Muin Literati Purge?
What about the officials you took down
using chaehong,
led by the Chief Royal Secretary,
under the guise of avenging
the deposed queen?
Have you forgotten
all that happened in those days?
the pain and suffering you caused?
It is all my fault.
I have absolutely no excuse…
for what happened.
Now you show remorse?
What more must I do
to absolve myself of my sins?
Though I am not sure
if I can be absolved of them at all.
The very thought of them…
torments me greatly as well.
That is why
I returned everything to order
with a revolt.
Your mother's tragedy.
Your late father
and the Han family's mistake
of putting you on the throne!
You!
You should never have been king.
It should have been me!
The throne should have been mine!
So that is what this was all about?
I see you wanted to be king, Uncle.
I have one question.
Why did you return to the palace?
There was
no place for me
to hide on this land anyway,
so I wanted to settle things with you
once and for all.
Very well.
Tell me.
What do you want?
I want your word
that you will uphold Jinmyeong's reign,
so he does not make the mistakes I did.
Then I will take full responsibility
and accept my dethronement.
I am prepared to do so.
What a just ruler you are.
Very well.
I will banish you
to where your mother is buried.
Very well.
If shouldering the weight of it all
is the way to atone for my sins.
Just as I thought,
I cannot leave you be, Uncle.
I may be a living criminal,
but you are
a true tyrant possessed by madness.
You sure have changed a great deal
after meeting the chief royal cook,
Your Majesty.
Here is the journal you asked for.
You will never eat such dishes again,
so consider this His Highness' mercy,
allowing you to keep your memory.
MANGUNROK
Cook Yeon.
Are you still alive?
The chief royal cook
greatly misses the hometown
she left behind.
How does "hwanseban," meaning
"food that brings one home," sound?
HWANSEBAN
My dearly beloved,
if…
you were to read this someday,
may you come back
to my side.
MANGUNROK
For then,
I will recognize you
at first glance.
For then,
my heart shall belong to you
from the very beginning.
You are alive,
Cook Yeon.
That is a great relief.
His Majesty is really alive?
The situation is not ideal,
but he is alive.
I gave him the butterfly ornament,
so he will know you are alive.
Then…
will His Majesty be exiled now?
How do you know that?
I heard he will be banished.
BANISH: TO SEND A CRIMINAL FAR AWAY
AS PUNISHMENT
The events are unfolding
just as they did in history,
even though
he didn't even initiate a purge.
At this rate,
he'll die shortly after being exiled.
I heard you came from the future.
Do you know what happens
after he is exiled?
The records say
he died shortly afterward.
I see.
It may seem like they are showing mercy,
but who knows what will happen to him
once he is banished?
Gong-gil.
We must save His Majesty, no matter what.
Will you please help me?
That damned man.
-He should be beheaded.
-Indeed.
Though the criminal Yi Heon
ascended the throne
by the mandate of the heavens,
not only did he neglect his duties,
but he also persecuted
and executed his subjects without cause.
As if that were not enough,
he committed the heinous impiety
of murdering
the Grand Royal Queen Dowager,
and just one day after his dethronement,
he committed treason.
Thus, he is hereby demoted
to the status of a prince as Yeonhuigun
and sentenced to exile in Ganghwa.
I remember.
Yeonhuigun.
You don't know the tyrant Yeonhuigun?
The worst tyrant of Joseon.
How did you know I would like this dish?
I studied Yeonhuigun.
I'm from the future.
Yeonhuigun.
That was me.
Cook Yeon.
I see now
that you recognized me
from the very beginning.
You do not look so content.
It would be crazy of me
to laugh in this situation.
Does that mean I am crazy?
Your Highness, it is finally over.
Congratulations.
A fire is not fully extinguished
until the last embers are put out.
We still have something to take care of.
Do you mean…
The thought of sparing his life
weighed on my mind.
You are truly very wise.
Lords Sung and Kim,
please remain in the palace
and watch over our new king.
-Lord Yoo, please prepare the soldiers.
-I will do as you command.
-Deok-chul.
-Yes, Your Highness.
While I am away,
make sure to take good care of Her Grace.
Yes, Your Highness.
Oh my, my lord.
Make way!
We only wish to make a living.
Step back!
I said step back!
You need not be so angry.
How dare they harm something
that belongs to me?
They should be taught a lesson.
Make way!
Cook Yeon.
What are you doing here?
Don't worry.
Go.
Go, now!
Hang in there.
You have to stay strong.
Bang!
Okay?
Do not do anything foolish.
I have a plan of my own.
Step back!
Cook Yeon!
My goodness. All right, we are leaving.
Hurry along!
Let us get going.
-Cook Yeon.
-Hurry!
Cook Yeon.
Cook Yeon…
Halt.
-Drag him out!
-Yes, sir!
I will not say much.
Blame the heavens.
Of course.
Just as expected, Uncle.
Now.
Your Majesty, are you unharmed?
You made it in time.
Here is your royal sword, Your Majesty.
My first prediction was correct.
My second one will be as well.
You will see.
I am certain
my uncle will come to check my dead body.
Eliminating him then
is the last thing I can do for Jinmyeong
as a dethroned king.
Oh dear.
I see I overestimated you, Your Majesty.
I thought you would have
a decent group of followers.
But this is it?
Unless you have other plans,
you will die here today.
Your Majesty!
Cook Yeon.
I'm here to save you.
Gong-gil and these men
are here to save you.
Gong-gil.
Cook Yeon!
Miss!
-Miss!
-Chief Royal Cook!
-Your Majesty!
Gil-geum.
What are you all doing here?
Gong-gil told us of the plan.
What?
All right then.
Let us have some fun!
Let us go!
The royal kitchen cooks and jesters.
What a useless bunch of fools.
Archers!
Shields!
Fire!
Now!
Strike down the rebels!
Oh my, miss!
Those damned bastards.
Spears! Forward!
-Step back!
-Stay away!
-Gochogaru!
-Cook Sim!
Throw the gochogaru!
Cook Yeon!
I am here!
Am I late?
No. You're right on time.
I will get to use these
to my heart's content.
Su for "hand," and tu for "throw."
Behold, sututan, you scoundrels!
Your Highness, we must retreat for now.
Those damned…
All because of that
wretched chief royal cook again!
Miss!
-We won!
It is not over yet.
Capture Grand Prince Jesan!
Heon!
Cook Yeon.
Do you remember
where we drank together
before you ascended the throne?
Wolyeongru.
Let us meet there.
If you do not come alone…
the chief royal cook will die.
How dare that damned bastard
take a woman hostage?
Your Majesty, I will go save her.
I will go as well!
-Me too!
Please let us join!
Miss!
I am the one my uncle wants.
-Your Majesty.
-Your Majesty, you cannot go.
It is dangerous!
Do not worry. I will return.
While I save the chief royal cook,
you all must eliminate
the rest of my uncle's men
and reclaim the palace.
Your Majesty.
-No, Your Majesty!
-Your Majesty!
Miss!
Attack!
Lord Sung. We received word
that Grand Prince Jesan was defeated.
What? His troops were annihilated?
Leave the rest to me and go!
We are heading to Gangnyeongjeon!
Are you not the assassin
from Salgoji Forest?
Then why did you side with the king?
Because what you lot were doing
was more foul than filth.
I will not die like this.
Not like this!
Your Highness.
What happened to the world
you promised us?
Do not stand back!
Strike down the rebels!
Your Majesty.
Please return safely.
I cannot believe that the palace
was reclaimed so easily.
We greatly underestimated
the dethroned king.
I yearned for a reign of peace.
But it was nothing but a fleeting dream!
Your Highness…
Is anyone there?
Your Grace.
You…
You are…
I am here to take revenge for my sister.
And also…
for all the women you used then discarded.
One who bears a sword with a grin
will eventually be struck by it.
I will never beg for my life
to you lowly scoundrel.
You wench!
Do you know how many lives you have taken?
I am but a jester, just like yourself.
Do not be ridiculous.
You have no right
to call yourself a jester.
That is not for you to decide.
This…
is for my sister.
It is all over, Chief Royal Cook.
This time, for once,
I stand with His Majesty.
WOLYEONGRU
I knew he would come.
The love that makes him
do anything for you.
It is so very touching.
Will having company on one's way to hell
make the journey more pleasurable?
I see you are unharmed.
That is a relief.
Step aside.
Uncle.
You took my cook
that even the Ming could not take.
Are you prepared to face the consequences?
Did you yourself come here prepared?
Let us see if you can reach me.
I will make you come to me.
MANGUNROK
Cook Yeon.
Not bad.
Your Majesty!
Cook Yeon!
Cook Yeon! Get away from here!
Hurry!
No.
I can't go on my own.
Do not worry about me.
Go!
MANGUNROK
No way.
Is this Mangunrok?
Next
is the potage.
"Mangunrok"?
They're recipes.
Today's special dinner menu
is doenjang pasta.
The dish I prepared today
is a German dish called schnitzel.
It is crunchy on the outside,
but moist and chewy on the inside.
These are the foods
I made for His Majesty.
I used butter instead of sesame oil.
It is just barley rice.
Why is this page torn?
HWANSEBAN
"My dearly beloved…"
My dearly beloved,
if you were to read this someday…
"…may you come back…"
…may you come back
to my side.
I don't believe it.
Mangunrok was written
by His Majesty?
-Do not just stand there. Get that wench!
-Yes, Your Highness!
Uncle.
It is not too late to sheathe your sword.
It is your great fortune
that you have escaped death
time and time again.
It is retribution for your sins
to die by my sword.
Uncle!
Power you cannot control
is nothing but a poison!
No!
Cook Yeon.
No.
Cook Yeon!
Cook Yeon.
Your Majesty…
Do not speak.
I actually…
didn't want to leave.
Where would you dare leave
without my permission?
I love you,
Your Majesty.
Cook Yeon.
I beg of you. Please open your eyes.
Please!
HWANSEBAN
Please open your eyes.
Please…
No…
No.
Please, no…
No…
Please.
No.
No, Cook Yeon…
The Mangunrok she desperately searched for
was my journal.
Why now?
Why?
No.
Cook Yeon.
Cook Yeon!
Wherever you are,
I will find you.
I will send you along with her!
Heon…
I should have been
the king of Joseon.
Uncle.
Please go in peace.
Your Majesty.
Please don't forget your promise
to find me.
WOORI UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
No!
Where am I?
A hospital?
Am I back?
This wound…
It wasn't a dream.
Then what about His Majesty?
What happened to him?
No!
Mangunrok.
Where is it?
I have to go back.
Ji-young.
You're awake.
Dad.
Do you know how worried I was?
Just a moment. Are you all right?
You can't move around all of a sudden.
Ji-young.
Stay home and rest
while I get some groceries, okay?
-Okay.
-I'll be quick.
THE REAL BASIC COOKBOOK
Cook Yeon!
Get away from here!
No. I can't go on my own.
Do not worry about me.
Go!
No!
No. Cook Yeon.
Cook Yeon.
I beg of you. Please open your eyes.
Please!
No…
YEONHUIGUN
FOOD EQUALS POLITICS…
DETHRONED KING OF JOSEON
"Yeonhuigun's body was never found"?
"Yeonhuigun went missing"?
History changed.
I might
be able to meet him again if I go back.
Give me your word.
Promise me…
that you will come back to me.
MANGUNROK
"My dearly beloved,
if you were to read this someday,
may you come back to my side."
No.
"My dearly beloved,
if…
you were to read this someday,
may you
come back to my side."
It's not working.
Why won't it work?
The bathroom.
"My dearly beloved,
if you were to read this someday…
may you come back to my side."
I'll show you.
Open up.
What if…
I want to come back but can't?
In that case,
I will find you.
I hope…
that wasn't our last day together.
ONE MONTH LATER
Oh, Chef Yeon.
Hey.
You look well.
Were you surprised to hear from me?
I guess a little bit.
What's up?
Nothing's up. It's just…
-Let's do business together.
-What?
Michelin has begun their selection process
here in Korea.
I'm sorry, but I'm not exactly
thinking about working right now.
If you can't work full-time,
then just one month.
Just until we find a decent chef.
If we don't receive
a Michelin star again this time,
the hotel will shut down the restaurant.
Please, Ji-young.
Can I see the kitchen?
Come this way.
Might as well.
I'll do it.
Chef Yeon.
May I taste the dessert?
It's just for a month though.
Okay.
And if you want a Michelin star,
this menu won't cut it.
I'll try developing a new one.
The dish you won during the competition?
No.
Fine dining that incorporates
Joseon royal cuisine.
You know how to cook royal cuisine?
This is Yeon Ji-young,
Enfin's new head chef.
-Hello, Chef.
No way.
Cook Eom!
Cook Maeng!
Cook Sim!
Cook Min!
Gil-geum!
Sorry?
My name is Sun-geum.
What?
SEO SUN-GEUM
This is unbelievable.
How can they look so alike?
Are they their descendants?
They look too much alike
for it to be a coincidence.
I'm Yeon Ji-young, and I'll be overseeing
the kitchen at Enfin.
I hope we get along.
La Poêle d'Or.
-Oh, the winner?
-For real?
-Oh, the--
-That's enough.
We're going to develop a new menu
for the upcoming Michelin evaluation.
And…
I plan on creating a dining course
inspired by the royal kitchen
that was in charge of serving meals
to the kings of the Joseon Dynasty.
I have a feeling
we'll do great as a team.
-I look forward to working with you.
Just like that,
I returned to the life I used to live.
But
my heart and my time
remained in the Joseon royal kitchen.
I took the royal cuisine I'd come across
as the chief royal cook
and the dishes His Majesty
had recorded in Mangunrok
to create a new menu.
I applied the techniques
I'd learned in Paris
toward developing a royal dining course.
And I named it
the Chief Royal Cook's Dining Course.
Chef Yeon, take a look at this.
NATURE-INFUSED MODERN ROYAL KOREAN CUISINE
CHIEF ROYAL COOK'S COURSE HIGHLY PRAISED!
Highly praised?
Chef!
Congratulations!
-She's awesome.
-Congratulations, Chief Royal Cook!
Three Chief Royal Cook courses.
Prepare your dishes, everyone.
-Yes, Chef!
Good evening, sir.
Did you make a reservation?
A table at 7 p.m. for Steve Im.
Great, thank you. Please follow me.
I heard there's a new menu here.
CHIEF ROYAL COOK
Modern Korean cuisine, Chief Royal Cook.
Yes, sir.
We've reinterpreted dishes
that were served to the king
as a modern course meal.
It's Enfin's signature course.
I'll order that.
Can I get two glasses
of mineral water first?
Yes, of course.
Chef Yeon.
The Chief Royal Cook course
for table seven.
It's Michelin.
He asked for two glasses of water
and had two phones.
Just do as you always have, okay?
-Yes, Chef!
The consommé looks great.
-Please plate it up.
-Yes, Chef.
The beef tartare with seaweed
gets soggy easily,
-so make sure to plate it on time.
-Yes, Chef.
-Slice it a bit thinner.
It's ready to be plated, so Cook Maeng…
-Excuse me?
-Sorry.
Chef Maeng, please prepare the garnish
for the bourguignon.
Yes, Chef.
-Dessert for table seven.
-Yes, Chef.
Chef.
The guest at table seven
said it tasted bad.
He says the meat is dry
and wants it remade.
What? He didn't even touch the food.
I'll serve him.
It has a great finish.
Hello.
I'm Yeon Ji-young, the head chef at Enfin.
He looks exactly like Im Song-jae.
And why are you here?
He's nitpicking here too?
Well…
You asked us to remake the short ribs
braised in wild grape rice wine
and ogolgye samgyetang.
Is there a problem with the food?
I see you didn't understand
because I was being indirect.
You called it modern cuisine
that holds the essence of nature.
I couldn't feel the nature you spoke of.
He's nitpicking over nothing.
They say it's impossible
to stop a human from lying.
You didn't even touch the food.
Are you saying I'm lying
without tasting anything?
I have to say,
that's quite an impressive way
to avoid evaluation.
You shouldn't cook if you lack the skill.
Are you even with Michelin?
How can someone like you be a judge?
What did you say?
You're crossing the line.
How can someone like you be a chef?
You know what?
I'll give you a proper evaluation today.
Blame your cooking.
What?
If what you say is true…
I will try it myself.
Who are you?
What? "You"?
Do you wish to be struck down
with a sword?
A sword?
Is he crazy? Why does he talk like that?
-What?
-Sir.
Let me take you to our suite.
Let go of me.
Consider this your lucky day!
-How dare you!
-Come with me.
-A suite?
-Yes.
Your Majesty.
Is it…
really you?
I came to keep my promise.
My promise to find you.
Look at you, acting all cool.
What about your seoksura, evening meal?
How could I enjoy it without you?
Come and taste it.
EPILOGUE
-Hey.
-Chef Yeon.
The Michelin guy really was a fraud.
-What?
-I called the police, and they took him.
I knew it.
What a jerk.
He deserves to pay
for messing around with food.
Cook Yeon.
I'm coming.
All right, I'll see you tomorrow.
Thank you for cooking.
My goodness, what's with all this mess?
Come and sit down.
It's just bibimbap.
"Just"?
It is a royal bibinbap
that I, the king of Joseon,
made for the first time.
It is called hwanseban.
Right.
Do not eat if you do not want to.
No. I will eat it.
Thank you.
Then…
Open up.
Does it
taste good?
It needs some brown butter.
"Blown batter"?
This is called beurre noisette.
You melt butter as if you're burning it.
This is such a fascinating brazier.
Shouldn't you change the way you talk?
How should I do that?
It's hard to believe,
but he's from the 1500s.
By the way, how did you find me?
Well…
How did he get here?
That is a secret.
That's not important.
Because we're together again.
BON APPÉTIT, YOUR MAJESTY
Subtitle translation by: Jennifer Jean Lim